<resources>
    <string name="app_name">dz6</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Izberite igru</string>
    <string name="random">Radi</string>
    <string name="tekst1">A world map is a scaled representation of Earth\'s surface, offering a view of continents, oceans, and countries in a single, comprehensive layout. This type of map shows the spatial relationships between different regions of the globe, allowing us to understand the geographic position, size, and shape of landmasses and water bodies relative to one another. World maps are usually presented in two dimensions, which can create distortions due to the challenge of representing a spherical Earth on a flat surface. Various map projections, like the Mercator, Robinson, and Winkel Tripel, are used to minimize distortions, each balancing factors like area, shape, distance, and direction differently.\n\nWorld maps serve many purposes: they are educational tools in classrooms, essential resources in geography, history, and geopolitics, and helpful in visualizing complex global data like climate patterns, political boundaries, population distribution, and trade routes. With advancements in cartography and satellite technology, world maps have become more detailed, allowing us to explore Earth\'s diverse environments and understand global interconnectivity. Digital world maps, often interactive and integrated with GPS technology, have transformed navigation and accessibility, making geography an essential part of our daily lives.A world map is a scaled representation of Earth\'s surface, offering a view of continents, oceans, and countries in a single, comprehensive layout. This type of map shows the spatial relationships between different regions of the globe, allowing us to understand the geographic position, size, and shape of landmasses and water bodies relative to one another. World maps are usually presented in two dimensions, which can create distortions due to the challenge of representing a spherical Earth on a flat surface. Various map projections, like the Mercator, Robinson, and Winkel Tripel, are used to minimize distortions, each balancing factors like area, shape, distance, and direction differently.\n\nWorld maps serve many purposes: they are educational tools in classrooms, essential resources in geography, history, and geopolitics, and helpful in visualizing complex global data like climate patterns, political boundaries, population distribution, and trade routes. With advancements in cartography and satellite technology, world maps have become more detailed, allowing us to explore Earth\'s diverse environments and understand global interconnectivity. Digital world maps, often interactive and integrated with GPS technology, have transformed navigation and accessibility, making geography an essential part of our daily lives.A world map is a scaled representation of Earth\'s surface, offering a view of continents, oceans, and countries in a single, comprehensive layout. This type of map shows the spatial relationships between different regions of the globe, allowing us to understand the geographic position, size, and shape of landmasses and water bodies relative to one another. World maps are usually presented in two dimensions, which can create distortions due to the challenge of representing a spherical Earth on a flat surface. Various map projections, like the Mercator, Robinson, and Winkel Tripel, are used to minimize distortions, each balancing factors like area, shape, distance, and direction differently.\n\nWorld maps serve many purposes: they are educational tools in classrooms, essential resources in geography, history, and geopolitics, and helpful in visualizing complex global data like climate patterns, political boundaries, population distribution, and trade routes. With advancements in cartography and satellite technology, world maps have become more detailed, allowing us to explore Earth\'s diverse environments and understand global interconnectivity. Digital world maps, often interactive and integrated with GPS technology, have transformed navigation and accessibility, making geography an essential part of our daily lives.\nA world map is a scaled representation of Earth\'s surface, offering a view of continents, oceans, and countries in a single, comprehensive layout. This type of map shows the spatial relationships between different regions of the globe, allowing us to understand the geographic position, size, and shape of landmasses and water bodies relative to one another. World maps are usually presented in two dimensions, which can create distortions due to the challenge of representing a spherical Earth on a flat surface. Various map projections, like the Mercator, Robinson, and Winkel Tripel, are used to minimize distortions, each balancing factors like area, shape, distance, and direction differently.\n\nWorld maps serve many purposes: they are educational tools in classrooms, essential resources in geography, history, and geopolitics, and helpful in visualizing complex global data like climate patterns, political boundaries, population distribution, and trade routes. With advancements in cartography and satellite technology, world maps have become more detailed, allowing us to explore Earth\'s diverse environments and understand global interconnectivity. Digital world maps, often interactive and integrated with GPS technology, have transformed navigation and accessibility, making geography an essential part of our daily lives.\n</string>
    <string name="displayButton">Display</string>
    <string name="Center">center</string>
    <string name="Top_text">World of Wonders: Mystical Creatures</string>
    <string name="contentDescription">Mapa sveta</string>
    <string name="Chose_one">Which creature interests you the most?\n
        1. Yeti (Abominable Snowman)\n
        2. Kraken\n
        3. Chimera</string>
    <string name="text1">A world map is a scaled representation of Earth\\\'s surface, offering a view of continents, oceans, and countries in a single, comprehensive layout. This type of map shows the spatial relationships between different regions of the globe, allowing us to understand the geographic position, size, and shape of landmasses and water bodies relative to one another. World maps are usually presented in two dimensions, which can create distortions due to the challenge of representing a spherical Earth on a flat surface. Various map projections, like the Mercator, Robinson, and Winkel Tripel, are used to minimize distortions, each balancing factors like area, shape, distance, and direction differently.\\n\\nWorld maps serve many purposes: the</string>
    <string name="choose2">""</string>
    <string name="hint">Choose one</string>
    <string name="Yeti">The Yeti, commonly known as the Abominable Snowman, is one of the most iconic mythical creatures in Himalayan folklore. This legendary being is often depicted as a large, ape-like figure covered in thick, white fur that allows it to blend seamlessly into the snowy landscape of the mountains. Descriptions of the Yeti vary, with some accounts portraying it as a massive creature standing over eight feet tall, while others depict a more human-like figure.\n\nLegends of the Yeti date back centuries, with local Sherpa communities recounting tales of a creature that roams the heights of the Himalayas, often seen as a protector of the mountains. It is said that the Yeti is a solitary creature, preferring the company of the rugged wilderness to that of humans. Many stories describe its eerie calls echoing through the valleys, leading to a sense of wonder and fear among those who hear them.\n\nDespite numerous expeditions aimed at finding concrete evidence of its existence, the Yeti remains an elusive figure, shrouded in mystery. Reports of sightings often come from climbers and explorers who claim to have encountered large footprints in the snow or heard strange noises in the dead of night. Some believe that the Yeti may be a relic of prehistoric times, a remnant of the giant apes that once roamed the Earth.\n\nIn contemporary culture, the Yeti has become a symbol of adventure and exploration, inspiring countless films, books, and documentaries. While many view the Yeti as a myth, its allure continues to captivate the imagination, representing the enduring human fascination with the unknown and the possibility that there are still mysteries waiting to be uncovered in the world’s most remote corners.\n\n2. Kraken\nThe Kraken is a legendary sea monster that has haunted the imaginations of sailors and explorers for centuries. Originating from Scandinavian folklore, this colossal creature is often depicted as a giant octopus or squid capable of wreaking havoc on ships that venture too close to its domain. According to tales, the Kraken resides off the coasts of Norway and Greenland, lurking in the depths of the ocean, waiting to strike unsuspecting vessels.\n\nSailors who claimed to have encountered the Kraken spoke of its immense size, with tentacles that could stretch for miles, wrapping around ships and dragging them beneath the waves. When the Kraken surfaces, it creates whirlpools, swirling currents that can quickly engulf even the largest of ships. The sheer terror of encountering such a beast was enough to fuel many myths and superstitions among sailors, who believed that the creature was a manifestation of the ocean’s untamed nature.\n\nThroughout history, the Kraken has been used as a metaphor for the unknown dangers of the sea, embodying humanity’s fear of what lies beneath the surface. It serves as a reminder of the vastness and unpredictability of the ocean, a realm that remains largely unexplored. Many modern depictions of the Kraken draw on the original legends, portraying it as a powerful and fearsome creature capable of causing destruction at will.\n\nIn literature and popular culture, the Kraken has been immortalized in numerous works, from classic literature to modern films. It has come to symbolize not only the dangers of the sea but also the mysterious and often frightening aspects of nature itself. The legend of the Kraken continues to captivate audiences, encouraging us to explore the depths of our oceans and confront the mysteries that lie within.</string>
    <string name="chimera">The Chimera is a fearsome creature from Greek mythology, renowned for its monstrous appearance and terrifying abilities. This legendary beast is often depicted as a grotesque hybrid, combining features from three different animals: the head of a lion, the body of a goat, and the tail of a serpent. This combination of attributes not only made the Chimera a symbol of chaos but also reflected the ancient Greeks\' fascination with the blending of different elements.\n\nIn mythology, the Chimera is described as a creature of immense power, capable of breathing fire and causing destruction wherever it roams. Its fierce nature and formidable abilities made it a formidable opponent, one that struck fear into the hearts of those who heard its name. The Chimera is most famously known for its role in the myth of Bellerophon, a hero who, with the help of the winged horse Pegasus, was tasked with defeating the creature. This epic battle became a legendary tale, symbolizing the struggle between humanity and the chaotic forces of nature.\n\nThe Chimera’s legacy extends beyond its mythological origins; it has been a popular subject in art and literature throughout history. Artists have portrayed the Chimera in various forms, emphasizing its monstrous features and the fear it inspired. In modern times, the Chimera has become a metaphor for the complexities and contradictions of existence, representing the duality of creation and destruction.\n\nFurthermore, the concept of the Chimera has transcended mythology, influencing various fields such as biology and genetics. The term \"chimera\" is now used to describe organisms containing cells from different zygotes, reflecting the creature’s nature of being a hybrid. This modern interpretation serves as a testament to the enduring impact of this mythical beast, reminding us of the interconnectedness of life and the mysteries that lie at the intersections of different forms.</string>
    <string name="Kraken">The Kraken is a legendary sea monster that has haunted the imaginations of sailors and explorers for centuries. Originating from Scandinavian folklore, this colossal creature is often depicted as a giant octopus or squid capable of wreaking havoc on ships that venture too close to its domain. According to tales, the Kraken resides off the coasts of Norway and Greenland, lurking in the depths of the ocean, waiting to strike unsuspecting vessels.\n\nSailors who claimed to have encountered the Kraken spoke of its immense size, with tentacles that could stretch for miles, wrapping around ships and dragging them beneath the waves. When the Kraken surfaces, it creates whirlpools, swirling currents that can quickly engulf even the largest of ships. The sheer terror of encountering such a beast was enough to fuel many myths and superstitions among sailors, who believed that the creature was a manifestation of the ocean’s untamed nature.\n\nThroughout history, the Kraken has been used as a metaphor for the unknown dangers of the sea, embodying humanity’s fear of what lies beneath the surface. It serves as a reminder of the vastness and unpredictability of the ocean, a realm that remains largely unexplored. Many modern depictions of the Kraken draw on the original legends, portraying it as a powerful and fearsome creature capable of causing destruction at will.\n\nIn literature and popular culture, the Kraken has been immortalized in numerous works, from classic literature to modern films. It has come to symbolize not only the dangers of the sea but also the mysterious and often frightening aspects of nature itself. The legend of the Kraken continues to captivate audiences, encouraging us to explore the depths of our oceans and confront the mysteries that lie within.</string>
    <string name="buttonIks">X/O</string>
    <string name="buttonMonopol">Monopol</string>
    <string name="buttonTekst">More</string>
    <string name="iksoks">X/O</string>
    <string name="p1">P1</string>
    <string name="p2">P2</string>
    <string name="p3">P3</string>
    <string name="p4">P4</string>
    <string name="p5">P5</string>
    <string name="p6">P6</string>
    <string name="p7">P7</string>
    <string name="p8">P8</string>
    <string name="p9">P9</string>
    <string name="prethodna_igra">1</string>
    <string name="vertiaclLine">|</string>
    <string name="lastwinner">X : O\n0:0</string>
    <string name="button">New game</string>
    <string name="choose">Wich box? ( P1, P2, ... , P9)</string>
    <string name="setO">O</string>
    <string name="setX">X</string>
    <string name="goBack">Go back</string>
    <string name="About">Dobrodošli u aplikaciju posvećenu igrama!\n\n            1. **Monopol** - Klasična društvena igra trgovine i strategije gde igrači kupuju, prodaju i grade posede sa ciljem da ostvare monopol i ostave protivnike u bankrotu.\n\n            2. **Iks-Oks** - Jednostavna, ali zabavna igra na mreži od 3x3 gde se dva igrača takmiče da spoje tri X-a ili O-a u red, kolonu ili dijagonalu.\n\n            3. **Prikaz Teksta** - Aplikacija nudi opciju da prikažete tekst po vašoj želji, za informativne ili edukativne svrhe.\n\n            Uživajte u igrama i zabavi kroz ovu aplikaciju!</string>
    <string name="Timer">Time remaining: 60</string>
    <string name="Rezultat">Score</string>
    <string name="TextName">2 </string>>

</resources>